<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rootTag>
<Award>
<AwardTitle>SCC-CIVIC-PG Track B: Rehearsing Natural Disasters through Games and Simulations</AwardTitle>
<AGENCY>NSF</AGENCY>
<AwardEffectiveDate>01/15/2021</AwardEffectiveDate>
<AwardExpirationDate>06/30/2021</AwardExpirationDate>
<AwardTotalIntnAmount>49911.00</AwardTotalIntnAmount>
<AwardAmount>49911</AwardAmount>
<AwardInstrument>
<Value>Standard Grant</Value>
</AwardInstrument>
<Organization>
<Code>05050000</Code>
<Directorate>
<Abbreviation>CSE</Abbreviation>
<LongName>Direct For Computer &amp; Info Scie &amp; Enginr</LongName>
</Directorate>
<Division>
<Abbreviation>CNS</Abbreviation>
<LongName>Division Of Computer and Network Systems</LongName>
</Division>
</Organization>
<ProgramOfficer>
<SignBlockName>Sandip Roy</SignBlockName>
<PO_EMAI>saroy@nsf.gov</PO_EMAI>
<PO_PHON>7032927096</PO_PHON>
</ProgramOfficer>
<AbstractNarration>Recent events requiring evacuations such as the Camp Fire in Paradise, California highlight the critical need to better prepare communities for life-threatening natural hazards (flooding, earthquakes and wildfires) that affect so many communities in California and the country as a whole. Resilience in the face of these dangerous events requires a variety of changes from personal behaviors to regional policies and infrastructure. Despite the high stakes, change in this realm has proven slow and illusive. This proposal addresses this challenge by providing a means for emergency officials, incident commanders and community members to explore alternative responses to different hazards through the use of scenario-based games. These games, often referred to as “digital twins”, probe the interdependencies between the networks of transportation, lifeline infrastructures of water, power, and communications, and organizational plans that need to align for effective response to urgent hazards. An interdisciplinary team of designers, civil engineers, policy experts, and community members  will create social games based on wildfire, traffic and communication simulations. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;The project's inter-disciplinary team will partner with organizations in Oakland and Bolinas, California who are seeking new ways to increase the ability of their communities to respond to wildfire evacuation events. Together, the team will co-develop the social games with the purpose of surfacing local insight, knowledge, and feedback. These games are far more than entertainment, rather, they are constructed as prototypes that are used to support a cycle of mutual learning between the community and the researchers. In doing so, the team will create more resilient communities by using these instruments in a novel way to address the long-standing, classic problem of the transition of cognition to action. This project will offer new lines of research into more humanized data simulations, rapid, and iterative policy exploration and use of design at a systems scale. The insights gained from this project will have applications for the many communities within California and the United States that need to develop ways to create more resilient communities prepared to take effective action quickly in response to recurring hazards.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;This award reflects NSF's statutory mission and has been deemed worthy of support through evaluation using the Foundation's intellectual merit and broader impacts review criteria.</AbstractNarration>
<MinAmdLetterDate>01/12/2021</MinAmdLetterDate>
<MaxAmdLetterDate>05/20/2021</MaxAmdLetterDate>
<ARRAAmount/>
<TRAN_TYPE>Grant</TRAN_TYPE>
<CFDA_NUM>47.070</CFDA_NUM>
<NSF_PAR_USE_FLAG>1</NSF_PAR_USE_FLAG>
<FUND_AGCY_CODE>4900</FUND_AGCY_CODE>
<AWDG_AGCY_CODE>4900</AWDG_AGCY_CODE>
<AwardID>2043357</AwardID>
<POR>
<DRECONTENT><![CDATA[<div class="porColContainerWBG"> <div class="porContentCol"><p>During the course of this project our team developed partnerships in the community of Bolinas, California and Oakland, California. The goal of the project was to support these communities? existing efforts related to wildfire evacuations. To this end, we developed several interactive prototypes that were intended to allow the communities to ?rehearse? a wildfire evacuation.&nbsp;<br />Our work had several components. First, we prototyped and developed a fully functioning interactive story to explore the issue of wildfire evacuation with community members. The interactive story featured several characters in the setting of Bolinas and Oakland and the audience was prompted to answer questions about the decisions made by the characters in each story. In doing so, the audience was able to learn about the best practices of wildfire evacuations in a low-risk, low pressure way. As part of this work stream we hosted a workshops with the Oakland Firesafe Council. The event was used as a way to iterate the prototype and develop a more interactive videogame.&nbsp;<br />In order to create a scaleable videogame, our team developed Traffic and Fire Models for the&nbsp; Bolinas area. In addition, we also created Communication Models using Anylogic to show how the intersection among fire risk, traffic capacity, and communications functions affected the time required for evacuation under different scenarios. Our team worked with two graduate students, Sae Mi Chang and Sena Soysal, to <span> </span>develop AnyLogic models that estimated the time required for evacuation of the population of Bolinas (1500) using different types of communications ? radio, ham radio, cell phone, Twitter/Facebook, door-to-door, cognition -- under different scenarios of communications access, fire location and progression, and number of vehicles per household.&nbsp; <span> </span><span> </span>What did we find?&nbsp;?<span> </span>Communication from Incident Commanders not as straightforward as seems?<span> </span>Simplicity of Game more critical than accuracy of all elements?<span> </span>Interactivity offered opportunities for additional discussions?<span> </span>Game itself a potential for community building?<span> </span>Under optimal conditions, with cell towers functioning and communications flowing to all groups, exit roads not blocked by fire or fallen trees, population of Bolinas (1500) could evacuate safely in 1.5 hours?<span> </span>Under conditions when cell tower was damaged and cell phones/internet was operating at 50% capacity, safe evacuation of population of Bolinas would take 5 hours?<span> </span>Under the worst scenario, when cell towers were totally dysfunctional with potential blockage of single exit by fire or fallen trees, evacuation of Bolinas population would take approximately 10 hours.?<span> </span>The intersection among location and progression of the fire, access to, and functionality of, multiple means of communication among residents and tourists in Bolinas, and number of vehicles per household used in evacuation is critical to determining the safe evacuation of the population of Bolinas.?<span> </span>Using modeling to identify the constraints imposed on the evacuation process under different conditions of access and functionality helps residents to consider other alternatives, such as sheltering in place and identify safe locations to do so before a wildfire occurs.<br />OutcomesThe project yielded several outcomes. The first applies to the way prototyping can be used to explore a range of topics. The games, as policy prototypes, enable bi-directional learning. That is, unlike traditional prototypes where the learning flows from user to researcher, in this case, we were able to use the games as both a teaching tool and a tool to gain more insights from the community. This bi-directional learning is enabled by educational content (known best practices) and provocations (elements that are intended to tease out discussions). In addition, we recognized the centrality of communications to the evacuation process enables both fire personnel and community residents to consider other alternatives for shelter in place, if communications are adversely affected by the fire or power shut-offs. Another key outcome is that fire personnel recognize that evacuation is a regional process, and identifying destination points before the fire is critical in a time-dependent event like wildfire.</p> <p>&nbsp;</p> <p>&nbsp;</p><br> <p>            Last Modified: 09/08/2021<br>      Modified by: Thomas&nbsp;Maiorana</p> </div> <div class="porSideCol"> <div class="each-gallery"> <div class="galContent" id="gallery0"> <div class="photoCount" id="photoCount0">          Images (<span id="selectedPhoto0">1</span> of <span class="totalNumber"></span>)           </div> <div class="galControls" id="controls0"></div> <div class="galSlideshow" id="slideshow0"></div> <div class="galEmbox" id="embox"> <div class="image-title"></div> </div> </div> <div class="galNavigation" id="navigation0"> <ul class="thumbs" id="thumbs0"> <li> <a href="/por/images/Reports/POR/2021/2043357/2043357_10713060_1631138765144_Story-Layout--rgov-214x142.jpg" original="/por/images/Reports/POR/2021/2043357/2043357_10713060_1631138765144_Story-Layout--rgov-800width.jpg" title="Interactive Stories"><img src="/por/images/Reports/POR/2021/2043357/2043357_10713060_1631138765144_Story-Layout--rgov-66x44.jpg" alt="Interactive Stories"></a> <div class="imageCaptionContainer"> <div class="imageCaption">Stills from the Interactive Stories</div> <div class="imageCredit">Tom Maiorana</div> <div class="imagePermisssions">Copyrighted</div> <div class="imageSubmitted">Thomas&nbsp;Maiorana</div> <div class="imageTitle">Interactive Stories</div> </div> </li> <li> <a href="/por/images/Reports/POR/2021/2043357/2043357_10713060_1631138255056_Bolinas_overview--rgov-214x142.jpg" original="/por/images/Reports/POR/2021/2043357/2043357_10713060_1631138255056_Bolinas_overview--rgov-800width.jpg" title="Bolinas Resilience Screens"><img src="/por/images/Reports/POR/2021/2043357/2043357_10713060_1631138255056_Bolinas_overview--rgov-66x44.jpg" alt="Bolinas Resilience Screens"></a> <div class="imageCaptionContainer"> <div class="imageCaption">Stills from the videogame, Bolinas Reslience.</div> <div class="imageCredit">Tom Maiorana</div> <div class="imagePermisssions">Copyrighted</div> <div class="imageSubmitted">Thomas&nbsp;Maiorana</div> <div class="imageTitle">Bolinas Resilience Screens</div> </div> </li> </ul> </div> </div> </div> </div>]]></DRECONTENT>
<POR_COPY_TXT><![CDATA[ During the course of this project our team developed partnerships in the community of Bolinas, California and Oakland, California. The goal of the project was to support these communities? existing efforts related to wildfire evacuations. To this end, we developed several interactive prototypes that were intended to allow the communities to ?rehearse? a wildfire evacuation.  Our work had several components. First, we prototyped and developed a fully functioning interactive story to explore the issue of wildfire evacuation with community members. The interactive story featured several characters in the setting of Bolinas and Oakland and the audience was prompted to answer questions about the decisions made by the characters in each story. In doing so, the audience was able to learn about the best practices of wildfire evacuations in a low-risk, low pressure way. As part of this work stream we hosted a workshops with the Oakland Firesafe Council. The event was used as a way to iterate the prototype and develop a more interactive videogame.  In order to create a scaleable videogame, our team developed Traffic and Fire Models for the  Bolinas area. In addition, we also created Communication Models using Anylogic to show how the intersection among fire risk, traffic capacity, and communications functions affected the time required for evacuation under different scenarios. Our team worked with two graduate students, Sae Mi Chang and Sena Soysal, to  develop AnyLogic models that estimated the time required for evacuation of the population of Bolinas (1500) using different types of communications ? radio, ham radio, cell phone, Twitter/Facebook, door-to-door, cognition -- under different scenarios of communications access, fire location and progression, and number of vehicles per household.    What did we find? ? Communication from Incident Commanders not as straightforward as seems? Simplicity of Game more critical than accuracy of all elements? Interactivity offered opportunities for additional discussions? Game itself a potential for community building? Under optimal conditions, with cell towers functioning and communications flowing to all groups, exit roads not blocked by fire or fallen trees, population of Bolinas (1500) could evacuate safely in 1.5 hours? Under conditions when cell tower was damaged and cell phones/internet was operating at 50% capacity, safe evacuation of population of Bolinas would take 5 hours? Under the worst scenario, when cell towers were totally dysfunctional with potential blockage of single exit by fire or fallen trees, evacuation of Bolinas population would take approximately 10 hours.? The intersection among location and progression of the fire, access to, and functionality of, multiple means of communication among residents and tourists in Bolinas, and number of vehicles per household used in evacuation is critical to determining the safe evacuation of the population of Bolinas.? Using modeling to identify the constraints imposed on the evacuation process under different conditions of access and functionality helps residents to consider other alternatives, such as sheltering in place and identify safe locations to do so before a wildfire occurs. OutcomesThe project yielded several outcomes. The first applies to the way prototyping can be used to explore a range of topics. The games, as policy prototypes, enable bi-directional learning. That is, unlike traditional prototypes where the learning flows from user to researcher, in this case, we were able to use the games as both a teaching tool and a tool to gain more insights from the community. This bi-directional learning is enabled by educational content (known best practices) and provocations (elements that are intended to tease out discussions). In addition, we recognized the centrality of communications to the evacuation process enables both fire personnel and community residents to consider other alternatives for shelter in place, if communications are adversely affected by the fire or power shut-offs. Another key outcome is that fire personnel recognize that evacuation is a regional process, and identifying destination points before the fire is critical in a time-dependent event like wildfire.             Last Modified: 09/08/2021       Submitted by: Thomas Maiorana]]></POR_COPY_TXT>
</POR>
</Award>
</rootTag>
